Merged salt is one algorithm used to sort the sequence of numbers.
It's part of divide and conquer algorithms.
So first, the sequence is divided further and further into halves.
Consider we have seven numbers that we need to sort inside an array or analyzed or whatever you want.
So we need to divide further the sequence into halves.
So we have this.
Have we divide them into halves?
The first four and the second third.
Three elements six four three seven in the first and five one two and the second.
Then we divide the sequence further and further into halves six four is in a half, three seven is another
half five one.
And another half and to another half.
We divide them into further and further into halves.
This is the division of the problem and to solve the problems.
So we have divided the big array into two halves into the smallest possible cells, and now we need
that division are complete.
After the division is completed, we start solving the sub problems and then we combine the solution.
This is what we have learned in the divide and conquer algorithms.
So next, the divided groups are combined.
So these are the divided groups we need to combine them.
So when being confined combined, each group's number are arranged so that they are ordered from the
smallest to the largest after combination.
So we combine that we compared these small elements and we.
Order them from the smallest to the largest of the combination in each sub have.
Three and seven as auditor, five and one, we we divide the five, one and five, then the groups with
multiple numbers are combined and the first numbers are confirmed.
So we compare three and four.
The first numbers, three and four will be compared.
So three is less than four.
The remaining girls have their first no compared in the same number, so.
We compare three and four.
We have six and seven, six is less than seven, so we put six and seven.
Here we have sought in the first half of that.
Then the remaining seven is move and the combining of the groups is repeated the recursively until all
numbers from one group.
We have one five here and we have two from here.
We can combine and start.
One and two, and then we add five.
So we compare one and two, and then we add five.
Then this is the combining of groups is repeatedly recursively until all the numbers from one group
becomes and form form one group.
OK.
So these are the two halves.
Now we need to combine them by sorting and adding them to their combined and sorted.
Date.
OK, so combining complete and the sequence has been sorted.
This concludes the Merge sort and this is the Merge sort algorithm dividing the problem into sub arrays,
solve the problems and start solving the problems and then combining them to a general solution.
Let's move to see how that how the merged sort complexity works and how to end sea and in Java.
Haitham.